Prashil Lonakar

prashil.lonakar@gmail.com | +91 7558615669 | Portfolio | LinkedIn | pune, Maharashtra

SUMMARY

Software Developer Engineer with 5 years of experience in designing, developing, building, unit-testing, optimizing effective web applications and Project Managements. Possesses expertise in efficient development processes by creating user-friendly, responsive UI and minimizing bug count by 40% within the last quarter.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: Angular, React, Node, Express, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, MySQL, AWS

Management & Bug tracking tools: JIRA, ClickUp, Bugzilla

Design Tools: Figma

API testing Tools: Swagger and Postman

Analytical & Product Tools: Git, Bitbucket, Google Analytics, Microsoft Excel

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bajaj FinServ, Pune

nov 2024 – present

Senior Development Manager

nov 2024 – present

Project: 3in1 App

Skill: Angular 16, Android (Kotlin).

- Design the Onboarding Micro-frontend Webform and Module-federation POC for SSO (common access-token) which is approve by cross-functional team for Implementation.
- Led a cross-functional team in the successful implementation of a Micro-frontend architecture using Webpack Module Federation, resulting in a 50% increase in scalability.
- Followed Agile methodology, closely work with PMO to understand product requirement which increase 20% reduction in implement time.

Orangebits Software Technology, Nagpur

june 2019 – nov 2024

Senior Software Engineer

june 2023 - nov 2024

Project: Mahaforest (Kiosk/Admin)

Skill: Angular 18, React 18.3.1, Typescript, Redux, Node.

Lead the team and develop the product in Angular and React, meeting strict deadlines and deliver product within 35 days.

Project: Humanest (Social media)

Skill: Angular 15

- Implement, design and launch the product within 6 months.
- Implemented strict security protocols for GDPR and HIPAA compliance and Attained AA conformance in accessibility standards, enhancing user experience and usability by 40%.
- Improved performance of reads to serve many live users and ensure a seamless user experience across different interfaces. Resulting increase in user-base by 20%.

Project: Erp Solution

Skill: Nest, Node, Express, MySQL, React 18, Redux

- Led teams of developers in enhancing product functionality and building UI and API services for Erp.
- mplement the backend with microservices using NestJs and Typescript. Which improve scalability by 30%.

Project: Rushividyabhyasam (E-learning).

Skill: Angular 14, React 16

• Led the team and work with product owner understand their needs, Reduced project time by 15%, ensure to meet timely delivery.

Software Engineer jan 2021 - june 2023

Project: Flipkart Health+ (Flipkart)

Skill: Angular 6, Angular 8

- Build a sustainable code base with efficient services consumable, resulting in an overall reduction of original code volume.
- Initiate Ultra SDK to introduce micro-frontend capabilities to increase scalability of application.

Project: PKI Signal to SDC (Pfizer)

Skill: Angular 13, React

- Build a sustainable and scalable code base, resulting in handling elastic search with 10 million records at a time efficiently.
- Work together with offshore software developers, understand client needs and develop the app accordingly. Which increases the user interaction and satisfaction by 50%.

Project: Play Function (E-commerce)

Skill: Angular 8

- Migrated/Digital Transformed the project from Angular ver.4 to ver.9, which led to a 40% increase in performance.
- Redesigned components for the main webpage, which led to a 30% increase in loading speed.

Project: HOSPITAL (Management)

Skill: Angular 8, NgRx, MongoDB.

• Collaborated with clients to understand their needs and create software solutions with Angular Localization to support multi-languages in the application.

Project: Resimpli

Skill: Angular 4, Angular 10, Angular 11, Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB

Introduce google maps and street-view in app, which result in increase of user engagement by 70%.

Project: Tree Census (Government)

Skill: React 17, Redux

Junior Software Engineer

june 2019 - dec 2020

Project: Sigma (Fleet Management)

Skill: Angular 9, Angular 11, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB

 Oversaw UI and API development for Sigma. Develop the common reusability filter list component which results in a reduction of code and efficiency by 25%.

Project: Daman Online Services (Daman & Diu State Gov.)

Skill: Angular 4, Angular 7, Node, Express.js, MYSQL

Migrated the project from Angular 4 to 7, which led to a 35% increase in performance

Project: RECL INDIA

Skill: Angular 8, Node. Express, MySQL

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Spot Award Orangebits
- Integrated Team Award Orangebits

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

PBCOE, Nagpur

July 2012 - Nov 2017

LANGUAGES

English, Hindi, Marathi